My name is Paola, I
live in a small
house in the forest.  My
town is located
at the foot of a
large mountain
range.  It's quiet here,
maybe boring for some
, but for me it's
home.  I came to this
valley to find
work and help from my
parents when I felt like I couldn't
cope on my
own.  I gave so
much of myself away that I
no longer knew who I was
.  But over time, I
found my own
voice.  Over the past
few weeks, the snow
has melted,
giving way to
spring.  I was looking forward
to this time.  Everything
came back to life, ready for a
new beginning.
Lately I've
made new friends
in the forest.  Our
neighbors' cat, Lily,
accompanies me on
walks in the woods.
She reminds me
to listen to
my feelings and
just be myself.    For
about three
years now, I have been diligently learning to
live an
everyday life.
I spent time
observing,
reflecting, and
waiting, and I came to
the conclusion that to live a
simple, fulfilling
life, you need to
embrace not only your
complexity, but also your
unique path, which
is rarely straight,
realizing what an
amazing person you are
now and who you are becoming
at every step.
The answer to what a
simple life is
cannot come from me
or anyone else
on this earth.  It
depends only on you
.  You need to find a
balance between the harsh
reality of this
world and the happiness and
joy that you have the
power to nurture.  This
means
being fully aware of the changes
you want to see
in yourself and others,
while being able to
rejoice in your journey,
the acts of kindness
around you, and the beauty of the
everyday world.  I
truly believe in
affirming
that the reality you
support with your
observations,
thoughts, and actions
will become the one you
live in.  And this
thought is both
comforting and frightening, because it
places the burden of responsibility on you
.
Or you can
see it as I do:
it's not a burden, but a sign of
your own power
to create your own
story.  All of our
lives
are limited in some way.
The greatest stories are
often lost in
the annals of history; they
are not grandiose or
outwardly impressive
.  But they leave a
legacy.
There are good lives
that are enjoyed
within realistic limits.
I can't go and
do anything
or become
anyone.  Not everything
is possible for me.  But I
can work on
my goals,
make informed
decisions, and
practice love.    In the
meantime, we
need to
support others,
as well as ourselves,
by telling our own
story.  It is our
duty
to help at the
local level.  And
this domino effect
can really change
the world.  It starts
in our hearts,
spreads to
friends, family, and
beyond.  I often hear
the phrase: "If only I could
leave everything behind."  And I
appreciate that such
statements inspire
people to dream and
think about
other realities.  This
will always be important.
But I know that for
me, in practice, I
can't just leave everything.
My responsibilities, my
job, my family, my
community.  And I've
come to the point where I don't
want to be anywhere but
here, in the midst of goodness
and darkness, somewhere in between
, finding
peaceful contentment
.  What made me
start this
channel was the
realization that a
simple, happy life
is not a place.  And I will
continue to
say this until my
last video.  I
sincerely believe this.  These are
changes that
transform our
daily lives.  Not
constantly wishing for
something else, but working
towards your goals,
accepting yourself and
your life along the
way.